<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 20:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 20:52:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Months to come</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumping-at-work&quot;&gt;Pumping at work&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/months-to-come.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/months-to-come.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Weeks</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/first-weeks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/first-weeks.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-a-photo&quot;&gt;Take a photo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a moment you will want to remember forever.  DonÎéÎ÷t forget to have a camera, smart phone, and chargers handy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;change-baby&quot;&gt;Change baby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be messes, but you will get the hang of diaper changes, and you will become fast.  Just remember: always keep at least one hand on the baby so they can’t roll off, dry with a tissue, and check that the ruffles are NOT tucked into the diaper around the legs.  At the beginning, Baby’s small stomach requires frequent feedings, and the small stomach/bladder combo require frequent diaper changes.  Make sure your diaper station is set up in advance, and that you have a good supply of all the disposable necessities.  Before Baby comes, set up everything and make sure you can reach everything (and the respective back-up stashes.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diapers&quot;&gt;Diapers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had a great experience with Pampers Swaddlers, which is what our hospital used as well.  We also tried Huggies Naturals, but those ended up leaking every time we used them.  We’ve never tried cloth diapers, but don’t forget that the option exists, and diaper laundering services have sprung up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wipes&quot;&gt;Wipes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of options out there, from some great brands.  We were looking for something for a baby with very sensitive skin, and went with a friend’s recommendation for WaterWipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tissues&quot;&gt;Tissues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, such as plain Kleenex, or any other option without lotion.   If you remember just one thing from this website, let it be this – dab dry that baby before putting a new diaper on!  The best wiping job that leaves some moisture on the baby may lead to a rash.  Dab, dab, dab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tushy-cream&quot;&gt;Tushy cream&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait until your baby gets a rash.  Just rub a bit of this stuff on the tushy to prevent redness, swelling, irritation, tears, and GUILT in the first place.  We tried several options, but like this brand in particular for lack of smell, good consistency, and results.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gloves&quot;&gt;Gloves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever uses you’re picturing right now, many of them will likely come true.  Sometimes a mess is too much to clean without them.  Sometimes you’re putting Orajel on teething gums and there isn’t a place to wash your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dirty-diaper-bags&quot;&gt;Dirty diaper bags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ones for babies are way too expensive to serve as the momentary receptacle of poop!  Find whatever you prefer, but we just got these ones meant for furry babies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-disposable-pads&quot;&gt;Small disposable pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to lay these on the portable pad, because mid-change peeing is a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vaseline&quot;&gt;Vaseline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially important if you have a circumcised newborn Baby boy.  We found that the large tubs get messy and are inconvenient; the little packets make portability and application far easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changing-pad&quot;&gt;Changing pad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ones with a border all around will help keep baby from moving around too much, but the ones with only side borders will be better once the baby is much longer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changing-pad-cover&quot;&gt;Changing pad cover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a couple; even with the disposable pads, you’ll find yourself needing to launder these quite frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;baby-boy-tepee&quot;&gt;Baby boy tepee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kind of gave up on these, but some people have better luck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mirror&quot;&gt;Mirror&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially after a few weeks, babies love seeing themselves in the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;toys-for-distraction&quot;&gt;Toys for distraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just some stuff to help soothe and calm a baby during diaper changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;laundry-basket&quot;&gt;Laundry basket&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there will be lots and lots of laundry.As long as we’re on this topic, don’t forget to get some baby detergent.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diaper-genie&quot;&gt;Diaper genie&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not perfect, and requires buying their bag refills, but helps keep the smells at bay.  If you’re breastfeeding, you’re delaying the really smelly poop – formula and solids are what really crank up the stink.  We didn’t want to fill up the genie bags too quickly, so non-diapers – tissues, disposable changing pads – go into just a regular garbage bin that we keep next to the diaper genie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diaper-genie-bags&quot;&gt;Diaper genie bags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going with the diaper genie, you will need these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diaper-genie-filters&quot;&gt;Diaper genie filters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going with the diaper genie, you will need these as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hand-sanitizer&quot;&gt;Hand sanitizer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because sometimes you just can’t get to the bathroom to wash your hands before closing that final diaper/piece of clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-outfits&quot;&gt;More outfits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be messes :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;swaddles&quot;&gt;Swaddles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to stick with swaddling, and your baby responds well to swaddling, godspeed.  If you’ve got a Houdini on your hands, get some good swaddle sacks (you may need to try a few) and don’t worry about how to fold your baby into a burrito.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feed-baby---set-up-your-feeding-station-for-breastfeeding&quot;&gt;Feed Baby - set up your feeding station for breastfeeding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feeding-pillow&quot;&gt;Feeding pillow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked the My Breast Friend; it’s secure and comfortable and absolutely perfect for a newborn.  However, something like a Boppy Pillow will evolve into other uses as Baby grows, such as propping them up to learn to sit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feeding-pillow-cover&quot;&gt;Feeding pillow cover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever pillow you choose, you’ll need a couple of covers to alternate with messes.  Another option, or an additional one, is to lay a blanket down on the pillow every time, thus preserving the cover and just washing blankets when a spit up or some other mess occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-bra&quot;&gt;Nursing bra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get something super comfortable for home wearing - you’ll be whipping them in and out all day and night, and your body is still adjusting to size and hardness changes.  We recommend two.  If you want a more supportive, fancier option for going out in public, but still having easy access to milk, we got this one upon a friend’s recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-night-gown&quot;&gt;Nursing night gown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby needs easy access at all hours to milk, you need something easy for milk pad insertion, and you also need something with lots of access to your lady parts to take care of yourself after birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-pads&quot;&gt;Nursing pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried several, and Lansinoh was the best designed as far as dimensions and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nipple-soothing-gel-pads&quot;&gt;Nipple soothing gel pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because sometimes you will be sore.  With time, however, feeding frequency and duration go down, and your nipples get more used to their new (but don’t worry, temporary!) job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blankets&quot;&gt;Blankets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you can never have enough baby blankets around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burping-cloth&quot;&gt;Burping cloth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer a specialized blanket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-chair&quot;&gt;Nursing chair&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These span size, comfort, and price tags.  Perhaps you alrady have a nice spot on the couch in front of the TV and don’t need this at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;water-for-mama&quot;&gt;Water for mama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wherever your feeding station, make sure there is a table for full glasses or bottles for Mama!  You’ll be feeding dozens of ounces of milk to your baby; you must replenish your own fluids.  This is also absolutely key to having a normal digestive system after giving birth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snacks-for-mama&quot;&gt;Snacks for mama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those dozens of ounces of milk also mean youÎéÎ÷re giving your baby calories from your own body.  This is great news for pregnancy weight loss, but each calorie of milk is roughly 20 calories, and you are going to need some healthy snacks around to satisfy your hunger and nutritional needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;charged-phone-within-reach-for-mama&quot;&gt;Charged phone within reach for Mama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes feeding time will be just bonding time, and sometimes it will be the only time you can reliably predict being able to call someone, buy something you need, check on Facebook, or do pretty much anything.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emergency-formula&quot;&gt;Emergency formula&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in case, who knows. Ask your Pediatrician which is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-your-feeding-station-if-pumping&quot;&gt;Set up your feeding station if pumping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pumping is one of the most dehumanizing activities out there.  Look at it this way, though – it’s the price for the best of both worlds if you’re breast feeding – you can provide breast milk to your Baby and still have some flexibility/freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pump&quot;&gt;Pump&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one works well, is available at many hospitals, and parts are ubiquitously available.  Make sure you’re familiar with how to use your pump ahead of time – you never know when a blocked milk duct or wanting to store some extra milk will come. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pump-parts&quot;&gt;Pump parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will come with the pump, but there are a few good reasons for buying additional ones.  The major one is fit.  Try the pump – you may need phalanges that are a larger or smaller size.  The other reason is convenience.  If you’re pumping multiple times per day, and you don’t have to sterilize your parts, you can store your parts in the refrigerator between feedings.  Ask your Pediatrician about Baby’s health and also about local water quality to determine weather you need to sterilize you parts, in which case microwave bags are a big help.  If you are not near a fridge, and don’t have time to wash parts between pumps, you may want to have several sets handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bottles&quot;&gt;Bottles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many to choose from, with so many different advantages and/or gimmicks.  We went with Tommee Tippee based on some of the review we read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;storing-bags-or-bottles&quot;&gt;Storing bags or bottles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bags are easiest – they are disposable, and stack nicely in the freezer.  If you want something not plastic, glass is an option, but there is a greater chance of breakage.  To get the best of both worlds we went with this stainless steel option. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pumping-bra&quot;&gt;Pumping bra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free your hands and your time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-bra-1&quot;&gt;Nursing bra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get something super comfortable for home wearing - you’ll be whipping them in and out all day and night, and your body is still adjusting to size and hardness changes.  We recommend two.  If you want a more supportive, fancier option for going out in public, but still having easy access to milk, we got this one upon a friend’s recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-night-gown-1&quot;&gt;Nursing night gown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby needs easy access at all hours to milk, you need something easy for milk pad insertion, and you also need something with lots of access to your lady parts to take care of yourself after birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-pads-1&quot;&gt;Nursing pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried several, and Lansinoh was the best designed as far as dimensions and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nipple-soothing-gel-pads-1&quot;&gt;Nipple soothing gel pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because sometimes you will be sore.  With time, however, feeding frequency and duration go down, and your nipples get more used to their new (but don’t worry, temporary!) job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blankets-1&quot;&gt;Blankets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you can never have enough baby blankets around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burping-cloth-1&quot;&gt;Burping cloth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer a specialized blanket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nursing-chair-1&quot;&gt;Nursing chair&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These span size, comfort, and price tags.  Perhaps you alrady have a nice spot on the couch in front of the TV and don’t need this at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;water-for-mama-1&quot;&gt;Water for mama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wherever your feeding station, make sure there is a table for full glasses or bottles for Mama!  You’ll be feeding dozens of ounces of milk to your baby; you must replenish your own fluids.  This is also absolutely key to having a normal digestive system after giving birth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snacks-for-mama-1&quot;&gt;Snacks for mama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those dozens of ounces of milk also mean youÎéÎ÷re giving your baby calories from your own body.  This is great news for pregnancy weight loss, but each calorie of milk is roughly 20 calories, and you are going to need some healthy snacks around to satisfy your hunger and nutritional needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;charged-phone-within-reach-for-mama-1&quot;&gt;Charged phone within reach for Mama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes feeding time will be just bonding time, and sometimes it will be the only time you can reliably predict being able to call someone, buy something you need, check on Facebook, or do pretty much anything.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emergency-formula-1&quot;&gt;Emergency formula&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in case, who knows. Ask your Pediatrician which is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prepare-your-feeding-station-for-formula&quot;&gt;Prepare your feeding station for formula&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formula&quot;&gt;Formula&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many options to choose from, and it’s not always clear what’s a gimmick and what’s an advantage.  Talk to your Pediatrician about which to try with your baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distilled-water&quot;&gt;Distilled water&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using powdered formula, you may want to have some distilled water around if your tap water is in any way suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formula-dispenser&quot;&gt;Formula dispenser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We haven’t tried, but were definitely tantalized by options like this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bottles-1&quot;&gt;Bottles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many to choose from, with so many different advantages and/or gimmicks.  We went with Tommee Tippee based on some of the review we read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blankets-2&quot;&gt;Blankets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you can never have enough baby blankets around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burping-cloth-2&quot;&gt;Burping cloth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer a specialized blanket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;play-with-baby&quot;&gt;Play with Baby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yay!!  Baby is clean, fed, and awake – time to have a few minutes of fun, which are also Baby’s learning time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;floor-map&quot;&gt;Floor map&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tummy time, and all sorts of future play.  This one is very comfortable in terms of both size and cushion, and is easy to wipe.  It also has designs on both sides, in case you get bored.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tummy-time-mirror&quot;&gt;Tummy time mirror&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Babies loooooove looking at themselves, though really you’re not going to see much reaction for a few weeks, until their eyes develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rattle&quot;&gt;Rattle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, Baby can’t see well.  This rattle is high contrast, and has the main colors babies see first.  It’s also super cute and soft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;put-baby-down&quot;&gt;Put baby down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crib&quot;&gt;Crib&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crib-sheets&quot;&gt;Crib sheets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cosleeper&quot;&gt;Cosleeper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cosleeper-sheets&quot;&gt;Cosleeper sheets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pillow&quot;&gt;Pillow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pillow-cover&quot;&gt;Pillow cover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;swing&quot;&gt;Swing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clean-bottles&quot;&gt;Clean bottles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dishwashing-liquid&quot;&gt;Dishwashing liquid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bottle-brush&quot;&gt;Bottle brush&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drying-rack&quot;&gt;Drying rack&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/day-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day 0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before Baby even shows up, do yourself a huge favor and prepare a few essentials that you’re going to need sooner than you probably think.  You’ll also get some key things done that will make you feel in control and able to focus on other things, like whatever it is that makes your particular pregnancy feel easier. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-up-for-amazon-prime&quot;&gt;Sign up for Amazon Prime&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During feedings, between rocking, in the moment right before you close your own eyes, you will realize that you need that one extra order of diapers, or a bigger size hat, or a new outfit for yourself.  A few taps and swipes with your thumb, and the stuff you need will arrive at your door during the time in your life when it’s just not that easy to go get anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install the Amazon app on your smartphone.  Mark our words, you will look at your phone with a whole new love and affection, and wonder how generations past made it through this whole New Parent thing without this portable, all-knowing, entertaining, pathway out of lonely moments.  You’ll see ;) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Prime also comes with crazy amounts of free, shareable file storage (you will be drowning in photos and videos in no time.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it comes with free shows and movies that you can stream, either as you veg through the rough days of pregnancy, visit the treadmill at the gym, or try to space out for a few minutes once Baby is here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;diaper-bag&quot;&gt;Diaper bag&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the bag, the stuff, and put it in your car or by the door.  Did you know that even with a perfect, healthy baby you’re asked to come see the Pediatrician only a day or two after you get home?  And even without the Pediatrician, once Baby arrives, the diaper bag should be a constant companion for even the shortest outings – you never know when plans change.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-diaper-bag&quot;&gt;The Diaper Bag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bag itself!  You’re going to be bombarded with cute diaper bags, and there are many out there.  However, think about what you are reallylooking for.  Something light – you will carry it a lot.  Something with LOTS of pockets ÎíÎñ you’ll often be in a rush, by yourself, and organization will be everything.  Something fairly soft – you will smoosh it into strollers, back seats, and under restaurant tables.  Because of this, our choice is actually a bag that’s not sold as a diaper bag per se, but is really a well-designed gym bag, and is cheaper than a lot of the diaper bag options out there.  A place for everything, and everything in its place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diapers&quot;&gt;Diapers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had a great experience with Pampers Swaddlers, which is what our hospital used as well.  We also tried Huggies Naturals, but those ended up leaking every time we used them.  We’ve never tried cloth diapers, but don’t forget that the option exists, and diaper laundering services have sprung up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wipes&quot;&gt;Wipes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of options out there, from some great brands.  We were looking for something for a baby with very sensitive skin, and went with a friend’s recommendation for WaterWipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tissues&quot;&gt;Tissues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, such as plain Kleenex, or any other option without lotion.   If you remember just one thing from this website, let it be this – dab dry that baby before putting a new diaper on!  The best wiping job that leaves some moisture on the baby may lead to a rash.  Dab, dab, dab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tushy-cream&quot;&gt;Tushy cream&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait until your baby gets a rash.  Just rub a bit of this stuff on the tushy to prevent redness, swelling, irritation, tears, and GUILT in the first place.  We tried several options, but like this brand in particular for lack of smell, good consistency, and results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gloves&quot;&gt;Gloves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever uses you’re picturing right now, many of them will likely come true.  Sometimes a mess is too much to clean without them.  Sometimes you’re putting Orajel on teething gums and there isn’t a place to wash your hands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dirty-diaper-bags&quot;&gt;Dirty diaper bags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ones for babies are way too expensive to serve as the momentary receptacle of poop!  Find whatever you prefer, but we just got these ones meant for furry babies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;portable-changing-pad&quot;&gt;Portable changing pad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So great for changing while out and about.  If you have an SUV, during warm weather the trunk makes the best changing station while out and about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;large-disposable-pad&quot;&gt;Large disposable pad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you seen some of those public changing stations?  Gross.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-disposable-pads&quot;&gt;Small disposable pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to lay these on the portable pad, because mid-change peeing is a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extra-outfit&quot;&gt;Extra outfit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially at the beginning, or when your baby is between diaper sizes, or when the weather is changing, you may want to bring multiple outfits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blanket&quot;&gt;Blanket&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will find that there is no such thing as too many blankets at the beginning.  You’ll need it to lay baby down on something homey and clean, to shade them from the sun, to wrap them between weighing and doc visit at the pediatrician’s office, to provide a burp cloth, and the list goes on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pacifiers&quot;&gt;Pacifiers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to decide if, when, and which to introduce to your baby.  Some Moms prefer to not try at all, or at least not during the first few weeks if breastfeeding, to avoid nipple confusion.  Some Moms prefer to give these hospital standard pacifiers, which are great for the ease of cleaning – every nook and cranny can be cleaned and dried easily.  In our case, we went with the Maam variety,simply because that is the only one our Baby took to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nose-frieda&quot;&gt;Nose frieda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Babies tend to hate this, but there’s nothing better for helping your Baby breathe when that little nose is stuffy.  Just don’t forget to get extra filters! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nail-clippers&quot;&gt;Nail clippers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you don’t want to keep them in your diaper bag, but you never know when you may need them.  At the beginning, don’t cut your Baby’s nails – their nails aren’t yet separated from their fingers.  During the first few weeks, just use an emory board to file the nails.  Once Baby is a bit older, clippers and scissors are both options.  We liked the scissors better, for more control, but own and often try both.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ziplock-bags&quot;&gt;Ziplock bags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you sort and organize all the items in the bag, and to protect the bag from getting dirty from things like tushy paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-things-in-bag&quot;&gt;List of things in bag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may sound silly, but write down a list of everything you like to have in your diaper bag, and keep it in one of the easily accessible pockets.  but you’re going to mess up that bag every day, and take things in and out of it.  When you’re tired and have zero time to spare, a checklist makes life easy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emergency-contacts&quot;&gt;Emergency contacts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you never, ever have to use this, but give your tired brain peace of mind – have an easily accessbile list of emergency contacts in the bag for when you’re out or when someone else is watching your baby on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breastfeeding-pads&quot;&gt;Breastfeeding pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some things you will want to keep in the diaper bag for yourself.  If you’re breastfeeding, it’s a good idea to keep a few of these handy if you forgot one or need a change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vaseline&quot;&gt;Vaseline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially important if you have a circumcised newborn Baby boy.  We found that the large tubs get messy and are inconvenient; the little packets make portability and application far easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;car-seat&quot;&gt;Car seat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not specialists in which ones to buy.  This is a large ticket item, and a longer commitment.  In our case, we just went with one of the highest rated ones by safety metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stroller&quot;&gt;Stroller&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big ticket item.  Once we knew which car seat we wanted, we chose a stroller system to go with it.  That being said, many strollers are compatible ÎíÎñ either with or without an attachment – with the top car seats.  A few other considerations would include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you going to be running with your stroller?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you going to go for long walks? Maybe pneumatic (air-filled) tires are the way to go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will you often drive your stroller around? If so, portability is key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-home-outfit-for-baby&quot;&gt;Going home outfit for baby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a ton of fun with this one :-). Chances are, your Baby will really only wear this once.  Make sure it’s appropriate for the car seat and the weather, and get some good photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nursery&quot;&gt;Nursery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Furniture – the possibilities are endless. A trip to a furniture store or two will help you decide on colors, dimensions, and storage options.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decorations – we didn’t mess around much with things like wall colors, but we had a great time with decals!  Decals are basically big stickers for your walls, furniture, or anything else.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See also our Change Baby section, and depending on whether/where you will be pumping, our Pumping section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/day-0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/day-0.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clothes</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumping-at-work&quot;&gt;Pumping at work&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/clothes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/01/01/clothes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
